hey what's up everybody jerem M Kowski
here welcome to the grow Your Life
podcast this is for coaches trainers and
mentors who want to get more clients
make more money in their businesses and
be more successful now what I want to
talk about today is a topic very
specifically that a lot of my clients
have had questions about and what I want
to do is I want to invite you into the
conversation with us this comes from my
client growth accelerator program which
I'd love to have you become a part of
that program it's our Premier coaching
group our Mastermind program where I
work with coaches mentors and trainers
to help them dial in their messaging
dial in their sales skills their
promotions to be able to get more
clients to be able to scale and make
multiple six and seven figures in their
businesses I've been doing this for over
21 years and I know exactly what works
we have a proven system that has worked
for our clients and that can work for
you as well now I want to talk today
about pricing pricing is a topic that a
lot of people have and here's the truth
if you price your stuff wrong it can be
detrimental in your business it can
cause you problems it can cause issues
that you don't want to have to deal with
later and so that's what I want to dive
into is about pricing and how to price
things right and what's the art of well
pricing in your business in your
mentorship business in your coaching
business your online course business so
that you can actually get more clients
and so that you can actually attract the
right people to you number one pricing
is a determiner to the quality of person
that you're going to get you want to
repel people that you don't want to work
with and I get it maybe you want to help
a lot of people you want to help
everybody but the truth is not everybody
deserves to work with you at the highest
level and I can tell you as somebody who
came from a position of I want to just
be the cheapest option to help everybody
that helps nobody when we do that
because we end up devaluing ourselves
and we end up having to work with people
that don't respect us they don't honor
us they don't have any desire to even do
any of the stuff that we say to do
listen if that's you today if you're
listening to this and you aren't going
to do anything that I talk about please
just do us both a favor and stop
listening I say that all the time
because that's the truth is I don't just
talk just because I like to hear the
sound of my voice I talk because I want
to get people results who actually take
action action takers history makers
people who are actually going to do
something with their business and so for
you in your coaching or your online
course business your pricing is very
important because it determines are
people going to actually take action
with the thing that they bought people
are more likely to take action with it
when they have to make an investment
when they have skin in the game and so
you don't want to be the cheapest option
you don't want to just get give
everybody all this information for free
and then think oh I'm helping everybody
or really cheap because the truth is is
that being the cheapest option people
just don't respect it and so here's what
I look at is I look at what is the level
of pricing that people are going to
respect in our business and I also look
at what do people pay in other
Industries what do they pay in other
business models and things like that and
so what I found is that basically
anything that's under $500 to $1,000
people don't respect at all is that they
they don't put a lot of of emphasis in
their mind as to this is something
that's valuable this is something that I
need to take seriously and so that's
what I recommend for coaches and course
graders to charge at least $500 to
$1,000 per thing that they sell if
you're selling one hour of your coaching
needs to be at least $400 to $500 if
you're selling a course it needs to be
at least $500 to $1,000 if you're
selling a coaching program it needs to
be at least $500 to
$2,000 minimum and listen some high tiet
coaching programs we sell even go as
high as 10 and
$20,000 and that's because not everybody
is meant to be in them now here's one
cool thing about that you can offer
payment plans you can offer people an
opportunity to make payments with you to
these different things so they don't
have to come up with the money all
upfront and that's one of the cool
things that you can do with pricing to
alleviate some of that pressure on
people is to help them by offering some
payment plans but you don't want to just
bend over backwards for every single
person and make an opportunity for
everybody who can jump in I've tried
that before I've tried it in my business
the problem is those people don't
respect us they don't respect what we're
doing and they don't actually respect
what they're investing in they're
entitled they think that everything
should be handed to them whereas the
people who actually make a significant
financial investment they're willing to
go through the right process and to
follow along and do the things that
they're supposed to do in their business
and so you don't want to be the cheapest
option attracting broke people
attracting people that are desperate
attracting people that quote unquote
need help but they're not willing to do
anything and they want you to do all the
work for them your heart may want to
help these people I get it I do I really
do because that was
me but at the end of the day not
everybody deserves to work with you and
so you want to repel those people based
on your pricing you want to repel them
based on that you don't want them to say
yes you want a reason for them to say no
if the reason why somebody says no is
it's too expensive they probably aren't
a good fit for what you're doing now
there's different levels of pricing that
we can do we can have different tiers of
offers and so that's what I want to
break down right now is I want to break
down some of those different tiers of
offers first off number one definitely
we can have some free offers and free
offers are great because they do give
you an opportunity to grow your email
list but I I see a lot of people putting
a lot of pressure on themselves around
their free offer trying to get that
perfect you want to iterate these as
quickly and with as little effort as
possible so that you can get volume
going out with different free offers a
podcast is a free offer a a a webinar is
a free offer YouTube videos those are
free content those are pieces of content
that people can watch they can consume
they can get value from next from a free
offer and if somebody gives you their
name and email address they're now
giving you some sort of a commitment
some sort of a reason that you get to
send them some information they're
giving you a piece of them a part of
them their their contact info to be able
to go get deeper into your ecosystem and
even with that you don't want to put a
lot of time and effort into these pieces
of of
offers again I get it you got a spirit
of Excellence you want everything to be
perfect you want it to impact people at
a high level can I tell you this you're
going to impact people at the highest
level when you don't put a lot of your
effort into your free stuff and you
really just iterate through that as
quickly as possible to be a little bit
more prolific overall the next level is
our low ticket offers which I say are
generally generally between 97 to $27
right here okay and then we have a tier
2 low ticket offer as well which can be
anywhere from 97 to
$297 and these go into two different
tiers this low ticket offer right here
this is just one level above a free
offer it's just some little bit of money
that people are paying to get a little
bit of access to you I see people though
they end up putting $10,000 worth of
value into their $27 program they put so
much effort into that the purpose Behind
these items all three of these right
here is sales and marketing for you to
build trust with people for them to see
you demonstrate what that value is like
to work with you long term and overall
okay now and by the way none of these
levels are going to make you any level
of profit and I want you to understand
that I want want you to get that through
your mind is that these are not profit
producing levels in your business
they are for reaching people for
connecting with people they help
liquidate some of your advertising cost
and that is
it because then what you're doing is
you're going to take a small percentage
of these people and you're going to
ascend them to something that is between
500 to
$2,000 right
here and then some of these people
you're going to ascend them to something
that might be say $75
to $20,000 up there and this is what we
call the value
ladder the value ladder of ascending
people to these different levels so this
anything below this point for sales and
marketing you want to get as much of
this out there as possible with as
little time effort involved at pushing
this and then what you want to do is you
want to build this right here once and
sell it to as many of these people as
possible my client growth accelerator
program I offer to people at at all of
the different levels of content in my
business I don't make a dime of profit
off of any of these levels right here
our profit comes from these two levels
up here and that's a business model
that's how you want to build your
mentorship and coaching business now
anything that you offer at these levels
they are always strictly for the purpose
of ascending people up to whatever the
next level is so I want you to keep that
in mind yes you can provide value at a
$297 program yes you can provide value
for 27 bucks and I do all the time yes
you can provide value for stuff that's
free but the purpose is for people to
see and to Taste and to understand what
it's like to go to a higher level with
you and then at that higher level and
the reason why we want to charge this is
because that's what people are going to
actually take seriously for the right
thing that you offer people can find
$500 to $2,000 to be able to do those
things they can find
7,500 to $20,000 if they're already
inside of that and they really want to
work deeper and you can offer a payment
plan on those levels you could offer
very reasonable payment plan $600 a
month uh you know 1,500 $1600 a month at
these different levels and now people
don't have to Pony up all of this money
up front and they can make an investment
with you and that's where your profit
margins start to come in at those levels
all three of these levels of pricing are
what I recommend my clients to and I
recommend they have some free offers to
grow their email list they got some low
ticket paid offers to build to build
trust and you might be saying Joe
Jeremiah this so much stuff I got to
create yeah but here's the thing is if
you understand how to create content
without putting a lot of time effort
into it if you understand how to tap
into a flow state where maybe you only
got 10 15 minutes to create a piece of
content but you get it done and you
don't overthink it and you learn how to
actually tap into your zone of Genius
which we Mentor people on in my coaching
program you can learn exactly how to
create offers like this without having
to invest even 10 hours even five hours
into it you can do so very simply on
just 5 to 10 hours a week and be able to
build a business that creates multiple
six and seven figures by doing this
exact system right here and this is
exactly what we teach our clients to do
this is exactly what I would encourage
you to do in your business the other
thing that you can do is you can design
all of this into a membership you can
create a membership program or some kind
of a recurring program of some kind
around all of this right here and when
you do that you can create a connection
with people to bring them into your
ecosystem and Ascend them to that
highest level you get to answer people's
questions you get to provide support and
accountability and build trust with
people on those levels the only reason
why you wouldn't do this is fear of what
other people think or it not working out
are you worrying that you're not going
to be able to impact the kind of people
that you want to impact I want you to
grow past that worry and fear grow past
the fear of missing out grow past that
juvenile thinking and that worry that
well I'm going to miss out on certain
things or there certain people AR going
to like me or they're going to wor
they're they're going to not want to
work with me listen that's one of the
biggest fears that we have as humans but
can I tell you this as a business owner
we got to grow past that worry and fear
we got to grow past that and focus on on
who are the people that I'm meant to
impact who are the ones that I'm meant
to connect with in my ecosystem that I'm
supposed to talk to that I'm supposed to
provide value to that I'm supposed to
make that connection with and then from
there we can take things far further to
the next level in our businesses listen
if you want to grow your coaching or
online course business and you're
serious about working with somebody who
has a proven track record and you don't
want to have to do a bunch of trial and
error you don't have to work about
what's the right thing to do am I going
to make a mistake here am I going to am
I do I what do I need to do to get this
right and that right I want to work with
you in my C accelerator program to help
you get the support the accountability
to be able to have consistent income
massive impact to dial in your messaging
and to create the kind of Life Time
freedom and Financial Freedom that's
possible for you like what my clients
have experienced in your business in my
accelerator program jump in now jump in
when there's an opportunity for you to
jump in we'll talk soon have a good one
everybody
[Music]
[Applause]